Esta lição 25 de Pimsleur Inglês 1.
Listen to this conversation. Excuse me, miss, is this
the road to Long Island? No, it isn't. The road you want is over there.
I'm sorry, I don't understand. Where is it?
It's over there. Go straight ahead, then to the left.
How far is it to Long Island? Not far, 30 or 40 miles.
Thanks. You're welcome. Listen again.
Excuse me, miss. Is this the road to Long Island?
No, it isn't. The road you want is over there. I'm sorry,
I don't understand. Where is it? It's over there.
Go straight ahead, then to the left. How far is
it to Long Island? Not far. 30 or 40 miles.
Thanks. You're welcome. In English, how do
you say "mila"?
Mile. Ask "cuántas miles"?
How many miles?
How many miles is it?
Ask if this is the road to Long Island.
Is this the road to Long Island?
Nova quer dizer new em inglês. Agora tente dizer
Nova York. New York.
York. New.
New York.
Now try to ask: É
esta a estrada para Nova York?
Is this the road to New York?
Say: Não, a estrada para Nova York No,
the road to New York fica
à direita.
Is to the right.
The road to New York is to the right.
Vá para a direita.
Go to the right.
A estrada que você quer.
The road you want.
Fica à direita.
Is to the right.
Ask, a estrada que eu quero fica à direita?
Is the road I want to the right?
Ou à esquerda.
Or to the left.
Vá para a esquerda.
Go to the left.
Depois para a direita.
Then to the right.
E depois. And then,
e depois adiante.
And then straight ahead.
Ask how far it is. Ask how far it is.
How far is it?
How far is it to New York?
São setenta milhas.
It's seventy miles.
Try to say. São oitenta milhas.
It's eighty miles.
Eighty. Eighty. It's eighty miles.
Essa é a estrada que você quer.
That's the road you want.
Say, eu preciso de gasolina.
I need some gas.
Quanto custa?
How much is it? Dois dólares
por galão. Two dollars
per gallon.
Sei. Então, then,
eu preciso de um pouco de dinheiro.
I need some money.
Agora você quer perguntar se você pode comprar algo em
Nova York. Tente dizer em Nova York.
In New York.
How do you say eu posso?
I can. I can.
Now ask eu
posso?
Can I?
Ask. Eu posso comprar algo?
Can I buy something?
Em Nova York?
In New York?
Can I buy something in New York?
Try to say, "Não, você não pode." No,
you can't.
You can't.
É assim que se diz.
Por quê? Listen and repeat.
Why? Why?
Why? Ask. Por quê?
Why? Porque é longe
demais. Por quê? Listen and repeat.
Because.
Cause. Cause.
B.
Because. Say, por quê?
Because.
Ask, por quê?
Why? Try to say,
porque é longe demais.
Because it's too far.
Because it's too
far.
Eighty miles.
Eighty miles. It's eighty miles.
E as lojas estão fechadas. Primeiro,
as lojas. Listen and repeat. The stores.
Stores. Stores. Say as
lojas. The stores.
Stores.
As lojas estão fechadas. Listen and repeat. The stores
are closed.
Closed. Closed. Stores.
The stores are closed.
Say again. As lojas estão fechadas.
Now try to say a loja.
The store. The store.
E agora loja de departamentos. Listen and repeat.
Department store.
Department.
Ment. Department.
Department store.
Say again. Loja de departamentos.
Try to say that the department stores are closed.
The department stores are closed.
Ask, por que?
Why? Try to say. Porque são dez horas.
Because it's ten o'clock.
E as lojas estão fechadas.
And the stores are closed.
Ask if the stores are closed.
Are the stores closed?
Não, as lojas estão abertas. Listen and repeat.
No, the stores are open.
Open. Open.
The stores are
open.
How do you say abertos?
Open. And how do you say
Fechadas. Closed.
Closed. Say,
as lojas estão fechadas agora.
The stores are closed now.
Ask if the department stores are open.
Are the department stores open?
Say, as lojas de departamentos estão abertas agora.
The department stores are open now.
Open. The department
stores are open now.
Em inglês, eles e elas são a mesma palavra.
Tente dizer: Elas estão abertas agora.
They're open now.
They are.
Say again. Elas estão abertas agora.
They're open now.
As lojas menores estão fechadas.
The smaller stores are closed.
The smaller stores.
The smaller stores
are closed.
How do you ask?
What time is it?
Answer: São nove horas.
It's nine o'clock. It's nine o'clock.
Ask if the stores are open.
Are the stores open?
Answer: Não, elas estão fechadas. No.
They're closed.
Ask,
por quê? Why?
Porque é tarde. Listen and repeat.
Because it's late.
Late.
It's late because it's late.
Try to say, "Não é tarde." It's
not late.
It's not late.
Mas as lojas estão fechadas.
But the stores are closed.
The stores are closed.
Say, Nova York fica longe.
New York is far.
Try to say, 85 milhas.
85 miles.
It's 85
miles.
And the
stores are closed.
Sei, eu quero comprar algo.
I want to buy something.
Meu marido quer comprar algo. Listen.
My husband wants to buy something. Now listen and
repeat. My husband wants to buy something.
Wants.
Wants. My husband wants.
My husband wants to buy something.
Quando uma pessoa fala sobre outra, nas palavras tais como want
se junta um som de s ou z. Diga outra
vez: meu marido quer comprar algo.
My husband wants to buy something.
Now try to say, "Ele precisa de um pouco de dinheiro." He
needs some money.
Needs. He needs.
He needs some money.
Try to ask: Do que ele precisa?
What does he need?
Need. What does he
Ele precisa de um pouco de dinheiro.
He needs some money.
He needs. Ele quer colocar
gasolina. Diga, ele quer comprar gasolina.
He wants to buy some gas.
How do you ask? Que horas são?
What time is it?
É tarde.
Is it late?
Answer: São dez horas.
It's ten o'clock.
Ask por quê?
Why? Porque minha esposa
quer comprar algo.
Because my wife wants to buy something.
My wife wants because
my wife wants to buy something.
Ela quer comprar algo.
She wants to buy something.
She wants.
Ask onde?
Where? Try to say.
Em uma loja de departamentos.
In a
department store.
In a department store.
Pergunte se as lojas estão abertas.
Are the stores open?
Answer: As lojas pequenas estão fechadas.
The small stores are closed.
As lojas maiores estão abertas.
The bigger stores are open.
The bigger stores.
As lojas de departamentos estão abertas agora.
The department stores are open now.
They're open now.
Elas estão abertas hoje à noite.
They're open tonight.
Elas estão abertas tarde hoje à noite.
They're open late tonight.
Ask. E amanhã?
And tomorrow?
Amanhã elas estão fechadas.
Tomorrow they're closed.
Ask. Onde ficam as lojas de departamentos?
Where are the department stores?
Try to say. Elas ficam na Avenida Parque.
They're on Park Avenue.
On Park Avenue.
Vá para a esquerda.
Go to the left.
E depois adiante.
And then straight ahead.
Sei, minha esposa quer comprar algo.
My wife wants to buy something.
Em uma loja de departamentos.
In a department store.
O que ela quer comprar?
What does she want to buy?
Algo para nosso menino pequeno.
Something for
our little boy.
Something for our little boy.
Pergunte-me se eu tenho dinheiro suficiente.
Do you have enough money?
Answer: Eu tenho oitenta dólares.
I have eighty dollars.
Mas isso não é suficiente.
But that's not enough.
That's not enough. Nova York é cara.
New York is expensive.
E minha esposa?
And my wife?
Minha esposa precisa de muito dinheiro.
My wife needs a lot of money.
Needs. New York
is expensive, and my wife needs a lot of money.
Nesta lição de inglês um se incluem exercícios de leitura.